<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Polish English Interpreting Services</title>
    <description>Polish to English, English to Polish interpreting, Polish interpreter, North Yorkshire, interpreting, Polish English translating,  English Polish interpreter, English Polish interpreting, Polish lessons, Yorkshire, Harrogate, Ripon, Northallerton, North East, Halifax, Bradford, Middlesborough, Knaresborough, Wetherby, York, Wakefield, Dewsbury, Thirsk, Leeds, Huddersfield, Hull, Sheffield.</description>
    <link>https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 23:07:26 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 23:07:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nothing but praise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“We have never received anything but praise for her professionalism and skill as a language interpreter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beata has gone out of her way to meet booking clerks and to build a positive working relationship with those who book her services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both patients and clinicians, recognising her skill, have either requested her services – or lamented the fact that she has not been available to meet their Polish language needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can commend her as an asset to any organisation that was considering employing her skills as a Polish Language interpreter.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;J.W.&lt;br /&gt;
Manager&lt;br /&gt;
HDFT&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/testimonial/2018/11/24/Testamonial-NHS/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/testimonial/2018/11/24/Testamonial-NHS/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why should I hire an interpreter?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you happen to work with Polish clients or employ skilled Polish people as part of your team?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When interpreting or translation requirements emerge, companies often feel obliged to ask their inhouse staff for help, as it is perceived to be cheaper, and easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, being able to speak two languages is not the same thing as being able to accurately translate sometimes complex, often critical content. Translation and interpreting is a very distinctive talent that professionals work hard to perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it is true that more and more people learn and have a very good level of English– it is worth bearing in mind, that when it comes to interpreting one language into another, especially in HR, legal or medical matters, you need much more than someone you think is good in a particular language.
An interpreter isn’t just a bilingual person; an interpreter is a language expert. They have a deeper understanding of the way language works. They also have training in professional conduct. The interpreter’s professionalism and expertise makes them more than just a person who knows a couple of languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A good interpreter ensures properly worded and accurate deposition. They are careful to maintain the same tone, inflections and emotions of each speaker, to ensure the message is understood correctly. A good interpreter remains impartial and treats all information as confidential. They won’t be led by his or her personal opinion or views even if they are different from those of the client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often encourage my clients to hire a professional interpreter with the following statement: “Let your client or employee say what they want to say, not what they are able to say”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your client or employee might hold an important piece of information; however when facing a language barrier, they might potentially spend more time and energy on understanding and formulating their ideas and therefore miss the important part. They might find it more challenging to understand an English native speaker who speaks relatively fast, using specialist terminology with their regional accent. Many clients or employees might miss the subtle points and may feel embarrassed to admit to it at a later date. A good interpreter will know how to solve a problem and when necessary, they will bring an issue to your attention.
Clients speaking their own language are able to express the whole range of nuances, knowing that an expert – the interpreter – is in charge of conveying their message accurately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real importance of good interpreting, translation and proof-reading is most obvious when things go wrong. An interpreting job done by colleagues, friends or family may seem cheap at first, but they could prove extremely costly in the long run. Quality is not expensive, but corrections often are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To summarise the thought on importance of accurate translation and interpretation, I will leave you with the following statement: Never assume! Always be certain your client or employee understands the questions and options you present to them. Make sure the information is conveyed in full, by a professional interpreter, whose job it is, to facilitate a smooth conversation. Speak to your client in their own language, and you will be certain nothing is left to chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beata Mulvaney&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specialist Legal and Medical Interpreter&lt;br /&gt;
Polish English Interpreting Services&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/blog/2018/11/22/why-should-i-hire-an-interpreter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/blog/2018/11/22/why-should-i-hire-an-interpreter/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Flawless</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“I was fortunate enough to instruct Beata as a translator on many cases for my law firm. Her work was excellent, professional, flawless. I have no hesitation in recommending her to you”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A.G.&lt;br /&gt;
Solicitor | Director&lt;br /&gt;
Truth Legal&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/testimonial/2018/11/22/Testamonial-Truth-Legal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/testimonial/2018/11/22/Testamonial-Truth-Legal/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beata put us all at ease</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“Whilst interpreting, Beata put us all at ease, we are very happy with the service she provided for us.  Would certainly recommend her services to other companies.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;M.S.&lt;br /&gt;
HR Manager&lt;br /&gt;
Associated Waste Management&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/testimonial/2018/11/19/Testamonial-AWM/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://polishenglishinterpreting.github.io/testimonial/2018/11/19/Testamonial-AWM/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Testimonial</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
